This part, the posterior, will grow much faster.
This is the neural tube.
This is the part here, at the front.
And this is the back part.
It's going to do this.
It's going to create, in fact, a kind of tearing, here.
The lower intestine, here, you see.
This is the allantois, and this is what we call the cloacal area, here.
The waste flows out through there.
And this phase of separation.
between my lower intestine and the allantois process
will modify the posterior part in its dynamics.
But it's driven by a differential growth speed
of the posterior part compared to the anterior part
maintained by the allantois and organized by the liver.
So again, we will see that one of the engines
for this entire system will again be the...
hence the importance of understanding this dynamic and
this diaphragmatic relationship and this
overall growth because it's an organ if we look at it, if we open a body,
the liver is huge in its dynamics, it becomes an organizer through its growth.
Here we describe
that the kidneys seem to ascend from their sacred origin to the
lumbar region, the adrenal glands are
induced by the liver's tilt which will create a growth field for
my adrenal glands which are large,
that descent together, and then at some point they have done their work,
it seems like they regress, but no, it's just that the others have grown.
This is how we should think in embryonic development; it's about changing references.
The kidneys are the growth of the posterior structures that come
to position them.
It seems like they are ascending.
But in reality, this is what has descended.
All this has grown.
So the drawing is not accurate.
This is what will develop.
We will place the urogenital system that we'll connect to this collecting duct.
We note that the kidney is a concentration of mesoderm.
Secondly, it undergoes a rotation due to the developmental movement related to...
and to my posterior neural tube, the liver is very important
in its
development since it's the one that will create compression from the upper part
to the lower part for evolution. I remind you that the liver
in an embryo is connected with the transverse septum, the
transverse septum
ascends high since it has an embryonic origin at the level of
C3 and
it doesn't move anymore; it's the whole system that grows around it that makes
it appear so
that it becomes pillars, since it doesn't move but it's everything
around that grows and it ultimately finishes at the level of
L2 L3, in fact, it's
but
the origin gives the impression that it is at this level. Then, it's all this enormous growth.
So, it's a huge fulcrum that we will need. And on top of that, you have
the liver
which develops and, at some point, becomes larger and larger. It establishes
compression from the mesonephric part. And
then, you have the metanephron
which does not receive the pressure from the liver. However, the posterior part grows
and emerges like this.
to find their position. Then the rest of the urinary tract,
so the bladder, differentiates
from the endoblast of the posterior intestine. Since here I have my intestine,
the cloaca,
the allantois, well we see that the speed here at the posterior of my
neural tube is so
important that it will separate, like tearing the space between
the part.
future rectum and the part
future bladder given by
the allantois. And in fact, the pouch here
will simply become
the bladder. Initially,
the bladder and the rectum,
were one.
It remained that way and then it did this.
And in this, it separated
the cloacal space
from the rectum and created
the setup. And the kidneys,
in fact, they remained there.
My two kidneys are there.
my metanephrons, and they become my fulcrum relative to my
posterior part of the pelvis.
So when I take the pathway at the kidney level,
I know that I have this entire longitudinal axis of the embryo.
When I place it at my sacrum, I have a point of leverage,
I place it at my renal lodge,
and in fact the work is about opening motility, that's it.
You see, in relation to my kidneys.
it's its first impulse
I'm compressed in my anterior part
this explains well its shape
the compression
is there
the retroperitoneal level
becomes a joint
created by two movements
one which is organized by the growth
longitudinal of my nerve tube
and two by the endodermic movement.
So that means the integrity of these two functions will depend on
this intermediate joint.
It's a joint between the ecto and the endo.
That means the parietal system is dependent on the mesodermic system.
That’s why it's a royal pathway, the mesoderm.